<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Mayuresh Savargaonkar</title>
    <link>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/media/icon_hu03f0715a26910b6acfc0d853c045da1e_34977_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>I got the Dearborn Difference Maker award!</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/difference_maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/difference_maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to thank the University of Michigan-Dearborn for recognizing me as a 2022 Difference Maker! I am the only graduate student winner for this year! I am truly humbled and honored to receive this prestigious award. I am deeply grateful to my advisor Professor Abdallah Chehade for his positive and continuous guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research on the safety of autonomous and connected vehicles is creating a difference! I try explaining some aspects in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=liHkUn6GrnE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details can be see at this &lt;a href=&#34;https://michigandifferencemakers.com/mayuresh_savargaonkar&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;exclusive page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the award:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annually UM-Dearborn selects student Difference Makers who are at the forefront of their fields. Nominated by faculty and staff, these individuals aren&amp;rsquo;t just outstanding students and alumni, they embody academic and professional achievement, integrity and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Blue! Go Dearborn!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruise&#39;s robotaxis blocked Sanfranciso downtown?</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/cruise_block/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/cruise_block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getcruise.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cruise&lt;/a&gt; is one of the leading companies developing autonomous vehicles and robotaxis. They also recently started advertising their &amp;lsquo;Fully autonomous robotaxis&amp;rsquo; in Sanfrancisco, CA after receiving a driverless CPUC license. Immediately a few days later we had reports of these robotaxis being pulled over by cops &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1DZL0i51tRs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;video here.&lt;/a&gt; What happened for the taxis to pull over ? Cruise has been silent for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, after reading a bit and consulting with experts, it looks like either a networking issue that is causing the V2X communications to fail or complex mapping error. Either all mapped end destinations were the same or the rasterized HD maps had some bugs. What really went wrong? No one (for now) apart from cruise! Although the issue looks to be mundane at first, there are several implications that one needs to think of -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens when the fleet expands? Can we have map free solutions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens in adverse weather conditions, if the communications fail, will the taxis make &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; decisions and avoid such roadblocks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens if the remote connections break down ? Can authorities unlock the vehicles and move them until Cruise employees arrive? They arrived within a few hours in the above case!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Cruise is a leading transportation company, I think it still needs to complete a learning curve that Waymo (and May mobility for some part) has undergone. Rather than criticizing Cruise, as always, we (the AV community) shall learn from these issues, develop safer solutions and move ahead! AVs are coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional reading from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/07/01/self-driving-cars-from-gms-cruise-block-san-francisco-streets.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2022/06/30/cruise-robotaxis-blocked-traffic-for-hours-on-this-san-francisco-street/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Techcrunch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NHTSA publishes first ever ADAS related crash report, what comes next?</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/nhtsa_probe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mayuresh-savargaonkar.github.io/post/nhtsa_probe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As more vehicles are sold with Driver Assistance features, unknown failures are on the rise. The &amp;ldquo;curse of dimensionality&amp;rdquo; critically limits our abilities to dive into the unknown of unknowns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many questions remain-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we test AI algorithms in these features ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can synthetic data help ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How realistic are the current safety metrics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to verify and validate ? Is ISO 21448 / UL 4600 enough?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we develop, use and exploit V2I and V2V communications?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing is certain- we need to critically accelerate the learning from such incidents. How to do that is the pressing question!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nhtsa.gov/press-releases/initial-data-release-advanced-vehicle-technologies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; from NHTSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6942855578893385728/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#selfdriving #autopilot #autonomousdriving #autonomousvehicles #data #safety #wallstreetjournal #ai #algorithms&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
